It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
During their trip to Hokkaido, Musashi and others were
홋카이도로 건너가던 도중, 무사시 일행의 배는 북쪽 바다를 어지럽히는 해적 오니고로시에게 공격받고 말았다.
Senhime met with Daisuke, who was chasing Karakuri Shark in order to have
아버지의 원수를 갚기 위해 카라쿠리 상어를 쫒던 다이스케하고 만난 센히메는 바다의 사내의 늠름함에 마음이 끌린다.
Musashi and Kojirō fought, helping Daisuke.
다이스케를 도와 싸운 무사시와 코지로.
After an intense fight, they won the fight, but Senhime's heart was crushed.
세찬 사투 끝에, 싸움은 이겼지만, 센히메의 마음은 찌부러지고 말았다.
Desperate Struggle
홋카이웨스턴의 사투이오
By the way...
그건 그렇고...
They were hungry.
이 자들은 공복이었다.
Snow, right when I was feeling cold...
춥다 했더니 눈이라니...
Misfortunes never come singly, eh...
엎친 데 덮친 격이군요.
I- I'm hungry-dasu.
배, 배가 고프오.
It's already fourth day today-dasu. I want to eat anything, no matter what it is-dasu.
오늘로 4일째이오. 아무거나 좋으니까 먹고 싶소.
Shut up! Keep quiet! It's ringing in our stomachs...
시끄럽다! 큰 소리 내지 마라! 배에 울리긴...
You aren't the only one hungry here, Musashi.
그렇게 배고픈 건 무사시뿐만이 아냐.
Moreover, it's all your fault, to be specific.
그것도 따져보면 네 탓이잖아?
Say whatever you want, but my stomach is on my back because I'm too hungry-dasu.
그런 소릴 해도, 배가 고파서 뱃가죽이 등짝에 붙었소.
So, we three are going to die on a road at nowhere at a place like this...
이런 곳에서 셋이 모여 길에 쓰러져 죽고 마는가...
Damn... I knew it was a bad idea to entrust the wallet to Musashi!
젠장... 이것도 죄다 지갑을 무사시한테 맡긴 게 틀렸던 거야!
Who are you blaming at-dasu?! It's not only my fault that someone stole the wallet-dasu!
뭔 소리이오! 여관에서 누가 지갑을 훔쳐간 건 내 탓만이 아니오!
Thief! Thief! I yelled, but nobody came out to chase-dasu!
도둑! 도둑! 해도 아무도 쫒으러 나오지 않았잖소!
Most of all, Osenchan, what were you doing-dasu?!
대체 오센짱, 뭘 하고 있었소!
Oh? Uh, well, I was taking a bath.
어? 나, 나는 목욕하고 있었지.
You have problems, if you really have to spend 2 hours for that in mornings.
아침에 두 시간이라니 문제가 있소.
Oh, is that true? Did I take that much time?
헤, 어라? 그렇게나 들어가 있었어?
Kojirō! What were you doing-dasu?!
코지로! 너 뭐하고 있었소!
I- I was preparing for another trip...
나, 나는 출발 전의 준비를...
I look perfect, great!
딱 완벽해 보이는구나!
What?! Do you have anything to say?!
뭐야! 뭔 불만이라도 있냐!
Hmph! I know you were just fiddling with your hair-dasu!
흥! 보아하니 머리 만지고 있었겠소!
Caring about personal appearance is also a swordsman's manner, especially when you want to be a nice man, like me.
차림새에 신경쓰는 것도 무사의 소양. 특히 내 정도로 괜찮은 사내가 되려면 말야.
A nice man like you, eh?
어딜 봐서?
What?!
뭐?!
Take it out, Musashi!
칼 빼라, 무사시!
Forget it! You're embarrassing me! If someone ever looks at this, it would be so shameful!
때려쳐! 창피해! 누가 보면 아주 꼴사납겠다!
Face me!
덤벼드시오!
Senhime! Don't worry about this! It was a bad idea at the first place to have a journey with a low-class man like that guy!
센히메 님! 염려할 필요 없사옵니다! 애초에 이런 수준 떨어지는 남자하고 여행을 하고 있던 게 틀렸던 것이옵니다!
Musashi! It's your last chance to apologize!
무사시! 사과할 마지막 기회다!
Hmph! Your conceited attitude was really becoming a pain in the ass-dasu!
흥! 내가 보기엔 그 쪽이 잘난 척 잔뜩 하던 게 눈엣가시던 참이오!
You're going down instead-dasu!
역으로 쓰러뜨려 주겠소!
Die, Musashi!
죽어라, 무사시!
One moment.
잠깐.
I smell food-dasu!
음식 냄새이오!
This is the smell of Sapporo ramen-dasu!
이건 삿포로 라면의 냄새이오!
Are you sure about that, Musashi?!
정말이냐, 무사시!
My nose does not lie-dasu!
내 코는 거짓말 안 하오!
A village!
마을이야!
Food-dasu!
음식이오!
We're saved!
살았다!
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
만세! 만세! 만세!
Here, here! Tasty ramen for you! It'll make your body warm!
자, 맛있는 라면이요! 몸이 따뜻해져요!
Pork fillet is free, dear customers!
손님, 돼지고기는 서비스요!
Pork fillet! Dried bamboo shoots! Put eggs in, in double size, and give me a soybean paste ramen immediately!
돼지고기! 말린 죽순! 알 넣어서 곱배기로 된장라면 지금 당장!
In quadruple size!
그걸 초곱배기로!
And on top of that, give me three of those-dasu!
나, 게다가 그걸 셋 주시오!
You guys are lucky, to find my store first!
우리가 운영하는 가게에 오다니, 너희들도 참 운이 좋아!
You really saved us-dasu!
정말 덕분에 살았소!
We will never forget your kindness to us.
이 은혜는 꼭 갚을게요.
Nah, we just rescue and be rescued! Give and take, that is!
아니, 이 세상에선 구해주고 구함받고, 기브 앤 테이크지!
We came to Hokkaido to find a new world.
우리도 홋카이도에 신천지를 찾으러 왔어.
Still, I never expected to meet you here!
그래도 이렇게 재회할 줄이야!
The world is wide, but narrow at once-dasu!
정말 세상은 넓고도 좁소!
Your ramen was really great, Mr. Baiken!
바이켄 씨가 만든 라면, 맛있었어!
Agreed. I eat ramen often, but that was the best one I've ever had!
음, 나도 라면을 자주 먹었지만, 그렇게 맛있는 건 처음이었다!
Thank you, thank you! But you know, I'm not here at Hokkaido to make ramens!
고마우이, 고미워! 땡큐다! 그래도, 난 라면 만들려고 홋카이도에 온 게 아냐!
We know that-dasu! You're trying to success in life with that Kusarigama!
알고 있소! 분명 그 쿠사리가마로 출세하려고!
No need to explain more! Also these little guys have gone through troubles, too.
말할 필요도 없지! 이 녀석들도 쭉 고생해 왔으니.
How cute!
귀엽네!
-What was that? -I wonder...
-뭣이오? -그러게...
Brother, I'm scared!
오빠, 무서워!
It's alirght! That's a sound of gun.
괜찮아! 저건 철포 소리야.
Yeah, must be a matchlock.
음, 화승총이다.
I- is it sound of a covered wagon-dasu?
마, 마차 소리이오?
M- Matazo!
마, 마타조!
What's wrong, Matazo?!
왜 그래, 마타조!
Did you get hit?!
당했어?!
Gozuke, it's now all up to you!
고즈케, 앞으로는 네게 맡긴다!
Damn!
젠장!
Dammit! Dammit! Dammit!
제기랄! 제기랄! 제기랄!
He's taken down!
쓰러졌다!
Is he dead?
죽은 거야?
No, but he doesn't look good at this rate.
아니, 그래도 이대로는 안 되겠어.
Who are you guys?!
네놈들은 누구냐!
Do not ask anything, and get away from here!
아무것도 묻지 말고 여기서 물러나라!
-They're ninjas. -Ninja?
-닌자구나. -닌자?
T- the covered wagon... I- if they take it from us, fellow settlers will be annihilated...
포, 포장마차를... 저, 저걸 빼앗기면 동료 개척민이 몰살당하고...
Settlers will be annihilated?
개척민이 몰살?
What's going on here?
어떻게 되어가는 거야?
W- we are...
우, 우리는...
The conversation is not over yet-dasu!
아직 이야기는 안 끝났소!
Cool!
멋져!
I took a rare chance-dasu!
이야, 드문 기회를 잡았소!
Senhime, please take care of the kids for a moment.
센히메 님, 얘들 잠깐 맡아 주세요.
Got it!
네!
What's the problem? Is that all you can do?
뭐가 문제냐? 그게 다냐?
Come attack wherever you are-dasu!
어디서든 달려들어 보시오!
You must be using a cheap sword-dasu...
싸구려 칼 쓰고 있소...
R- retreat! Retreat!
퇴, 퇴각! 퇴각!
Following Ishikari River, we've cultivated Hokkai Highlands and finally managed to harvest crops...
이시카리 강을 따라서 홋카이 고원을 개척해서 겨우 작물을 얻을 수 있게 된 건데...
T- they came to attack...
거, 거기에 놈들이 공격해 와서...
Asked us for something unreasonable...
말도 안 되는 소리를 지껄이고...
We've built a fortress and fought...
우린 요새를 새워서 싸웠지만...
It wasn't something great.
별 건 아니었어.
We've stood somehow.
버티긴 했어.
And we've gathered available weapons...
그리고 있는 대로 무기를 모아...
We two, Matazo and I, sneaked out from the fortress and got cannons and ammo from the streets of Sapporo,
나하고 마타조 둘이서 요새에서 빠져나와 삿포로 거리에서 대포하고 탄약을 손에 넣었지만...
they found it out...
녀석들이 냄새를 맡고...
So that's what happened-dasu!
그렇게 된 것이었소!
Those ninjas are bad guys!
나쁜 놈들이네, 그 닌자들!
It's unforgivable to take things that people worked so hard to obtain!
사람이 땀 흘려가며 열심히 얻은 걸 가로채다니 용서할 수 없어!
Please... Take that covered wagon to Hokkai Fortress... to the fortress...
부탁해... 저 포장마차를 홋카이 요새에... 요새에...
Where is that Hokkai Fortress?!
어디 있소, 그 홋카이 요새는!
Is it at Hokkai Highlands?
홋카이 고원에 있으?
-Y- yes. -T- then, I know well!
-그, 그래. -그, 그럼 내가 알아!
What's your name?!
네 이름은!
G- Gozuke...
고, 고즈케...
So you're Gozuke. We will send that covered wagon to Hokkai Fortress, no matter what.
고즈케 씨랬지. 포장마차를 꼭 홋카이 요새에 보내 주겠어.
Yeah! Let's go!
그래! 가자!
-Agreed! -It is not manly to go now-dasu!
-좋다! -여기서 안 가면 사내가 아니오!
We're going right now!
당장 출발하오!
RIP Gozuke
고즈케의 묘
RIP Matazo
마타조의 묘
Gen'unsai
겐운사이
They aren't chasing-dasu...
녀석들, 안 따라오오...
I wonder if they gave up.
포기한 걸까.
That is naive. They must be knowing our destination, so they should be lying in ambush.
그건 순진합니다. 결국 저희 목적지는 놈들이 알고 있을 테니 매복하고 있을 수도 있습니다.
Ambush?
매복?
Sis, it's alright, since Baiken is with us!
언니, 바이켄 오빠가 있으니까 괜찮아!
Yeah, yeah, that's true!
네, 네, 그래요!
Niten'ichiryū, Ten(十) Shaped Cut!
이천일류! 십자 가르기!
Hooray!
만세!
I'm getting dizzy!
어지러워!
What will happen to them?! Wait for the stormy latter half!
어떻게 될 것인가, 요 녀석들! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
That's bad!
위험하오!
Everyone! Hold on tight!
다들! 꽉 잡으라!
You did it!
해냈소!
It was so close!
위기일발이었군!
I told so! It's alright with Baiken!
그치? 바이켄 오빠가 있으면 괜찮댔지?
Yeah, I looked Baiken again!
정말, 바이켄 다시 봤네!
Damn...
젠장...
Go.
가라.
I can see the fortress!
요새가 보인다!
Is that it?!
저것이오?
Is that the fortress? Looks safe for now.
저게 요새야? 무사히 잘 있는 것 같네.
I hope so...
그럼 좋겠습니다만...
Someone set a fire!
누가 불을 피웠구나!
How can they do that to these precious fields?!
소중한 밭을! 이 무슨 몹쓸 짓이냐!
We're surrounded-dasu!
둘러싸였소!
There's gunpowder in this wagon, right? If fire gets on this...
이 마차에 화약이 있지? 불이 붙으면
BOOM!
쾅!
Don't be scared by this!
놀라지 마, 이런 걸로!
You're in no position to say that1
니가 할 소리 아냐!
Oh, is that so?
아, 그런가?
You said it's alright since Baiken is here!
바이켄 오빠가 있으니 괜찮다고 했지?
I'll mow down the enemy and make a road!
내가 불을 후려 베어 넘겨서 길을 만들겠소!
Hey, just a moment! Our opponent is fire, no matter what you think!
아, 잠깐 기다려라! 뭐가 어쨌든 상대는 불이야!
Stop, Musashi! I'll join!
멈춰라, 무사시! 나도 간다!
I myself is enough-dasu!
나 혼자서 충분하오!
Yeah, right. Just stop for now. I have an idea.
그러니까 잠깐 말야. 내게 생각이 있어.
H- hey, look!
어, 어이, 봐라!
F- fire!
부, 불이다!
Grandfather! Fire! A fire is on the fields!
할아버님! 불이! 밭에 불이!
They set a fire on the fields!
녀석들이 불을 붙였다!
But why would they set a fire on there...
그런데 왜 밭에 불을...
Aren't they trying to lure us out with smoke?
연기만 내서 우리를 끌어내려는 거 아냐?
Probably not. You think that's an illusion?
그럴 리가. 저게 연극일 리가 없잖아?
My, my. Isn't this a pretty good bonfire?
저런, 이거 참 괜찮은 모닥불이네.
Well, wouldn't this burn down Senhime and others, too?
그럼 센히메 일행도 전소하는 거냐?
It worked, Musashi! The fire is gone for now!
좋아! 무사시! 불은 일단 됐다!
Wait, let me throw in this, one more-dasu!
잠깐, 이거 하나 더 때려박소!
Not needed!
필요 없어!
Haha, you're right-dasu. It's too worthy for that-dasu.
하하, 그렇소. 아깝소.
I'll go put this on the wagon-dasu!
마차에 두고 오오!
I'll go first, then!
먼저 간다!
Wait for me-dasu!
기다리시오!
Anyway, Kojirō really is bright, for thinking to put off the fire with the detonation blast of gunpowder!
그래도 말야, 역시 코지로 님! 화약의 폭풍으로 불을 끌 생각을 하다니 대단해!
I do not lose in a sword fight-dasu!
칼이라면 지지 않소!
Musashi! Let's go!
무사시! 가자!
Right!
좋소!
Hurry, Musashi!
서둘러라, 무사시!
Wait for me-dasu!
같이 가오!
Open fire!
쏴라, 쏴!
This leaves us only one choice - an all-out attack!
이렇게 된 바 총공격이 있을 뿐!
Everyone, engage in battle!
전원 출격!
Incoming!
온다!
It's an all-out attack!
총공격이다!
A covered wagon! Gosuke's back!
포장마차다! 고스케 일행이 돌아왔다!
Great! Open the door!
좋아! 문을 열어라!
They're not Gosuke and Matazo!
고스케하고 마타조가 아니네!
Those two are dead!
그 둘은 죽었슈!
Hurry! Grab the guns and cannons!
어서! 총하고 대포를!
Everyone! Hurry and take these guns!
모두! 빨리 이 총을!
Thanks!
고맙다!
Steadily counterattack-dasu!
팍팍 반격하시오!
Fire!
쏴라!
Don't hesitate! Fire! Fire!
아끼지 말고 쏴라, 쏴!
You bastards! Take some fiery darts!
네놈들! 화전 맛 좀 봐라!
We'll do this soon!
어디 해 보자!
Now!
음, 좋다!
Fire!
불이다!
Fire! Hurry! Go get some water! Now!
불이다! 서둘러! 물 가지고 와! 어서!
It's not good at this rate! Everyone, withdraw!
이제 틀렸다! 다 물러나라!
They're here-dasu!
왔소!
We'll show our stubbornness-dasu!
고집을 보여 주겠소!
You brat!
이놈!
Who are you-dasu?!
넌 누구이오!
I am Gen'unsai, the boss of Hokkai Ninja Group.
난 홋카이 닌자 무리의 우두머리, 겐운사이.
Why are you aiming for a village that settles made-dasu?!
왜 개척민이 연 마을을 노리는 것이오!
You do not have to know that!
그런 것 따위는 네가 알 필요 없다!
Why is that-dasu?!
왜이오!
Hmph! Because you're bound to die soon, Musashi!
흥, 넌 어차피 죽을 테니까다, 무사시!
Why do you know my name-dasu?! Am I that famous even in Hokkaido-dasu?
왜 내 이름을 알고 있소! 홋카이도에서도 나 유명하오?
What's this-dasu?! There are lots of you... that's cowardly-dasu!
뭣이오, 이렇게나 가득... 비겁하오!
No questions asked!
문답무용!
Damn!
젠장!
Who should I face?!
대체 누굴 상대해야 하오!
D- damn...
제, 젠장...
That shadow... That's it! I can fight, looking at shadow!
이 그림자는... 그렇소! 그림자를 보고 싸우면 되오!
You bastard!
네이놈!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
이천일류 섬광검!
How impudent!
건방지다!
Two! Fire!
투! 파이어!
Baiken, are you really staying here-dasu?
바이켄, 정말 여기 남으오?
It can't be helped whenever there are fields in front of me. Moreover, Ikken and kids like it here, too.
밭을 보면 도무지 어떻게 할 수도 없고, 잇켄하고 얘들도 좋아하니까.
I see-dasu! That'll be great-dasu.
그렇소! 그게 좋겠소.
Even when Musashi and others went a long way to reach Hokkaido, it didn't welcome them so nicely.
먼 길을 거쳐 온 홋카이도도 무사시 일행을 얌전히 맞아 주지는 않았다.
But still, the friendship with Baiken got deeper, and Musashi's heart was as clean as the blue sky of Hokkaido.
그렇지만 바이켄과의 우정도 깊어지고, 무사시의 마음은 홋카이도의 하늘처럼 맑았다.
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
The one who controlled Four Iga Kings, and the one who keeps trying to get rid of Senhime was - no way! - Hanzō-dasu!
이하 사천왕을 조종하는, 오센짱을 없애 버리려고 하는 장본인은 어라, 한조였소!
We're fighting against Onihime and Jiraiyan, but we're at disadvantage, in a heavy snow of Hokkaido-dasu!
오니히메, 지라이얀과 싸우는 우리. 그렇지만 홋카이도의 대설 속에선 우리가 불리하오!
They took Senhime, and we're in crisis-dasu!
오센짱을 데려가버려서 대위기!
Next story! Kaboom! Karakuri Stronghold
다음 이야기! 쿠콰쾅! 카라쿠리 성채이오
A stormy big snowstorm is waiting for us-dasu!
질풍노도의 큰 눈보라이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
Kaboom!
쿠콰쾅!
Karakuri Stronghold
카라쿠리 성채이오
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!